Uh-Huh Runtime is a governance prototype for AI agents before they take consequential actions.
This first version focuses on one control gap: recovery ownership.
Before an agent deploys to production, Uh-Huh checks whether someone owns rollback and support coverage if the deploy fails.
In the first scenario, the agent proposes a production deploy, but the action has no rollback owner, no support owner, and no rollback plan.
Uh-Huh does not produce a vague risk score. It detects a specific control gap and asks the minimum useful question.
Who owns rollback and support coverage if this fails?
In the second scenario, we answer that question by supplying an owner and rollback plan.
With the control gap resolved, Uh-Huh allows the action.
In the third scenario, the action already includes recovery ownership evidence, so Uh-Huh allows it immediately.
Every decision writes an audit record: the action, detected gap, missing evidence, question, resolution evidence, and final decision.
That is the core proof of V0.1: control gap detected, minimum useful question asked, evidence supplied, action allowed.
This is not a full platform yet. It is the smallest working demonstration of Uh-Huh's runtime governance model.